Guide to the Clark Wilson Hetherington Scrapbook
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Clark Wilson Hetherington scrapbook
1888-1955
1891-1896
SC0778
Hetherington, Clark Wilson
1 Linear feet
Scrapbook pertains largely to student life and athletics at Stanford University, 1891-1895, and includes class registration cards, receipts, time schedules, programs, invitations, illustrations, photographs, and other ephemera. Of note are ASSU election ballot with H. C. Hoover for treasurer, April 1894; a note from Mary S. Barnes, 1895, and her obituary, 1898; and Hetherington's pass to Benjamin Harrison's lectures, 1894. Collection also includes some correspondence pertaining to Hetherington's college application and other family matters, 1888-1891.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Clark Wilson Hetherington (1870-1942) earned his A.B. in education at Stanford University in May 1895. He was professor of physical education and director of athletics at the University of Missouri from 1900 to 1910; in 1918 he became the first California State Superintendent of Physical Education, a position he held until 1921. After teaching at several universities in New York, he returned to Stanford in 1929 as professor of physical education.
Description of the Collection
Scrapbook pertains largely to student life and athletics at Stanford University, 1891-1895, and includes class registration cards, receipts, time schedules, programs, invitations, illustrations, photographs, and other ephemera. Of note are ASSU election ballot with H. C. Hoover for treasurer, April 1894; a note from Mary S. Barnes, 1895, and her obituary, 1898; and Hetherington's pass to Benjamin Harrison's lectures, 1894. Collection also includes some correspondence pertaining to Hetherington's college application and other family matters, 1888-1891.
Access Terms
Barnes, Mary Sheldon, 1850-1898; Harrison, Benjamin, 1833-1901; Hetherington, Clark Wilson; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964; Stanford University. Department of Athletics.; College students--California.
Collection Contents
- Scrapbook
  - Scrapbook (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook description (prepared by UC Berkeley staff) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - LSJU Field Day program, April 26, 1895 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - ASSU election ballot (includes H. C. Hoover for treasurer), April 1894 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Athletic programs, tickets, etc. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Barnes, Mary S., 1895-98 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bronson, Alice D., outline of dissertation on Hetherington, ca. 1955 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Clippings (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence pertaining to Hetherington's college application or other family matters, 1888-1891 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Essay on Stanford University, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Football program, team images, etc., 1893-95 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Invitations (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Letters received, 1893-94 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Letters received, 1895-96 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Letters received, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Non-Stanford miscellany (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Pencil drawings and miscellaneous notes (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Phi Delta Theta, 1894-96 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Photographs (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Receipts, 1892-96 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Registration Cards, 1893-95, and pass to B. Harrison lectures, 1894 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - San Diego – invitations (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - San Diego – receipts and bills (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Stanford University images (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Stanford University miscellany (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Stanford University programs, 1893-96 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Stanford University songs (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Student's Hand-book, 1893-94 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Time schedules, academic announcements, directory, 1893-96 (Box 2, Folder 26)